Dylan Peet

San Francisco, CA | 860.309.2377

<u>dylanpeet@gmail.com</u> I <u>linkedin.com/in/dylanpeet</u> I <u>dbpeet.github.io/portfolio</u>

Summary Statement

Dylan is a systematic and adaptable thinker with a track record of achieving results while improving team cohesion and processes wherever he goes. His technical skills, problem solving prowess, and humanities-honed analytic orientation allow him to engage thoughtfully with any challenge.

Skills / Tools

Languages: JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS

Server-Side & Database: Express.js, Node, MongoDB, Mongoose, PostgreSQL

Libraries and Frameworks: React, Django, jQuery, Bootstrap **Workflow Management and IDE**: Git, Github, Visual Studio Code

Additional Tools: NPM, Homebrew, Trello, Heroku, Jira, Adobe XD, Photoshop, MS Office, G Suite **Management**: Leadership through empathy, active listening, advocacy, and adaptability. Mentorship and performance accepting. Sales management. Process development and improvement

and performance coaching. Sales management. Process development and improvement.

Technical Projects

BarApp, partner concept project

GitHub Repository | Heroku-Deployed App

- Bartender point of sale application built with Django and PostgreSQL that allows a user to add drinks to a bar tab, save tabs by customer name, and search for cocktail recipes (served by an external API).
- My partner and I stretched ourselves for this project, we were assigned to make a "bar app" but chose to make a point of sale app rather than a bar discovery app because we wanted to take on a more complicated back end challenge that was different from in-class projects.
- This project taught me about the complexities of handling less-than-ideal API responses, relational database savvy, and it was the project where GitHub collaboration clicked for me.

Git Sum Dim Sum, partner concept project

GitHub Repository | Heroku-Deployed App

- Dim sum restaurant discovery app built with Express, Node, Mongoose, and MongoDB, with Google Maps API integration.
- The EJS I learned on this project helped me to excel with React later in the course.

Experience

Exploratorium (2013 - 2019) San Francisco, CA

- Frontline Assistant Manager (January 2017 March 2019)
 - Managed the performance of five direct reports and supervised a team of 50+ regular, seasonal, and on-call staff alongside a leadership team of 15.
 - Credited with saving the museum's relationship with our largest tourism partner by revamping our sales incentives strategy, leading to a 20% increase in sales.
 - Proposed and implemented a policy tracking document that ensured that decisions made by the leadership team were appropriately communicated and tracked from conception to implementation.
 - Served on the museum's Staff Advisory Council for a term-limited tenure of two years, advising the Executive Director, advocating for the ideas and needs of the museum staff at large, and contributing the best line to the museum's current mission statement.

- Frontline Supervisor (September 2015 January 2017)
 - Added direct reports and bookkeeping to my responsibilities.
- Guest Services Coordinator (June 2014 August 2015)
 - Supervised floor staff, providing performance coaching and customer service recovery.
 - Provided major change management support when the staff of the guest services, museum stores, and membership sales departments were combined into a single new job description.
- Guest Services Associate (March 2013 June 2014)
 - Provided service and support to the museum public, business guests, and museum staff.

Peet's Coffee & Tea, Retail Associate (2012 - 2014) San Francisco, CA

SFMOMA, **Public Programs Intern** (May - August 2010) San Francisco, CA Researched future program concepts, wrote, edited and designed collateral materials, produced and managed events.

Dorfman Projects, **Gallery Manager** (June 2008 - August 2009) New York, NY Managed an inventory of approximately 1500 artworks, sales bookkeeping, handled and installed artworks, shipped and insured sold works, photographed artworks and exhibitions, managed web presence, wrote promotional copy, and coordinated with artist's studios and collectors.

Like the Spice Gallery, **Gallery Manager** (December 2006 - August 2008) Brooklyn, NY Wrote press releases, coordinated art fair participation, produced events, coordinated with artists and collectors, hired and supervised interns, handled and installed artworks. Curated the exhibition *After Everything* June-July 2008. Curated and Managed the LTS/Dylan Peet at *Bridge Miami Beach Art Fair*, December 2008.

Education

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive (June-September 2019) San Francisco, CA 12-week program developing fluency in multiple frameworks, libraries, and stacks. Built two personal projects and three team projects from conceptualization to wireframes, ERDs, program design, styling, and deployment.

City College of San Francisco, Intro to Programming (January-May 2019) San Francisco, CA Introduction to computer programming and problem solving techniques using Python, algorithm and program design, control structures, functional and object oriented programming.

Bard College, Center for Curatorial Studies (2009-2011) Annandale-on-Hudson, NY Studies in contemporary art and culture with a focus on institutions, equity, and art history.

Syracuse University, BFA, Media Art, Syracuse, NY

Completed thesis projects in both the video art and photography programs, additional in-depth coursework in philosophy, art history, sociology, and psychology.

Certificates

University of California Irvine, Introduction to Project Management Principles and Practices Specialization (February 2018 - March 2019) Irvine, CA / online

Four course specialization covering the basics of project management including identifying and managing product scope, building work breakdown structures, project budgeting, identifying and managing risks, and understanding the project procurement process.

University of Helsinki and Reaktor, **Elements of AI** (January 2019) Helsinki Finland / online Introduction to AI concepts and methods.